In this video we'll talk about
在这段视频中 我们要讲
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
how to fit the parameters theta
如何拟合逻辑回归
for logistic regression.
模型的参数θ
In particular, I'd like to
具体来说 我要定义
define the optimization objective or the
用来拟合参数的
cost function that we'll use to fit the parameters.
优化目标或者叫代价函数
Here's to supervised learning problem
这便是监督学习问题中的
of fitting a logistic regression model.
逻辑回归模型的拟合问题
We have a training set
我们有一个训练集
of M training examples.
里面有m个训练样本
And as usual each of
像以前一样
our examples is represented by
我们的每个样本
feature vector that's N plus 1 dimensional.
用n+1维的特征向量表示
And as usual we have
同样和以前一样
X 0 equals 1.
x0 = 1
Our first feature, or our 0
第一个特征变量
feature is always equal to 1,
或者说第0个特征变量 一直是1
and because this is a
而且因为这是一个分类问题
classification problem, our training
我们的训练集
set has the property that
具有这样的特征
every label Y, is either 0 or 1.
所有的y 不是0就是1
This is a hypothesis
这是一个假设函数
and the parameters of the
它的参数
hypothesis is this theta over here.
是这里的这个θ
And the question I want
我要说的问题是
to talk about is given this
对于这个给定的训练集
training set how do
我们如何选择
we choose, or how do we fit the parameters theta?
或者说如何拟合参数θ
Back when we were developing the
以前我们推导线性回归时
linear regression model, we use the following cost function.
使用了这个代价函数
I've written this slightly differently, where
我把这个写成稍微有点儿不同的形式
instead of 1/2m, I've
不写原先的1/2m
taken the 1/2 and put it inside the summation instead.
我把1/2放到求和符号里面了
Now, I want to use
现在我想用
an alternative way of writing
另一种方法
out this cost function which is
来写代价函数
that instead of writing out
去掉这个平方项
this squared and return here,
把这里写成
let's write here, cost of
这样的形式
H of X comma
（具体公式请看屏幕）
Y, and I'm going
to define that term cost
定义这个代价函数Cost函数
of H of X comma Y to be equal to this.
等于这个
It's just equal to just one half of the square root error.
等于这个1/2的平方根误差
So now, we can see more
因此现在
clearly that the cost
我们能更清楚的看到
function is a sum
代价函数是这个Cost函数
over my training set, or
在训练集范围上的求和
is 1/m times the sum
或者说是1/m倍的
over my training set of this cost term here.
这个代价项在训练集范围上的求和
And to simplify this
然后稍微简化一下这个式子
equation a little bit more, it's gonna
去掉这些上标
be convenient to get rid of those superscripts.
会显得方便一些
So just define cost of
所以直接定义
H of X comma Y to
代价值(h(X), Y)
be equal to 1/2 of
等于1/2倍的
this square root error  and the
这个平方根误差
interpretation of this cost function
对这个代价项的理解是这样的
is that this is the
这是我所期望的
cost I want my learning
我的学习算法
algorithm to, you know,
如果想要达到这个值
have to pay, if it
也就是这个假设h(x)
outputs that value it
所需要付出的代价
this prediction is H of
这个希望的预测值是h(x)
X, and the actual
而实际值则是y
label was Y. So just
干脆
cross off those superscripts. All right.
全部去掉那些上标好了
And no surprise for linear
显然 在线性回归中
regression the cost for you to define is that.
代价值会被定义为这个
Well the cost for this
这个代价值是
is, that is 1/2
1/2乘以
times the square difference
预测值h和
between what are predicted and the
实际值观测的结果y
actual value that we observe
的差的平方
for Y. Now, this cost
这个代价值可以
function worked fine for linear
很好地用在线性回归里
regression, but here we're interested in logistic regression.
但是我们现在要用在逻辑回归里
If we could minimize this cost
如果我们可以最小化
function that is plugged into J here.
代价函数J里面的这个代价值
That will work okay.
它会工作得很好
But it turns out that if
但实际上
we use this particular cost function
如果我们使用这个代价值
this would be a non-convex function of the parameters theta.
它会变成参数θ的非凸函数
Here's what I mean by non-convex.
我说的非凸函数是这个意思
We have some cost function J
对于这样一个代价函数J(θ)
of theta, and for logistic
对于逻辑回归来说
regression this function H here
这里的h函数
has a non linearity, right?
是非线性的 对吧？
It says, you know, 1 over
它是等于 1 除以
1 plus E to the negative theta transfers
1+e的-θ转置乘以X次方
X. So it's a pretty complicated nonlinear function.
所以它是一个很复杂的非线性函数
And if you take the sigmoid
如果对它取Sigmoid函数
function and plug it in
然后把它放到这里
here and then take
然后求它的代价值
this cost function and plug
再把它放到这里
it in there, and then plot
然后再画出
what J of theta looks
J(θ)长什么模样
like, you find that
你会发现
J of theta can look like a function just like this.
J(θ)可能是一个这样的函数
You know with many local optima and
有很多局部最优值
the formal term for this
称呼它的正式术语是
is that this a non convex function.
这是一个非凸函数
And you can kind of tell.
你大概可以发现
If you were to run gradient
如果你把梯度下降法
descent on this sort of
用在一个这样的函数上
function, it is not guaranteed
不能保证它会
to converge to the global minimum.
收敛到全局最小值
Whereas in contrast, what
相应地
we would like is to have
我们希望
a cost function J of theta
我们的代价函数J(θ)
that is convex, that is
是一个凸函数
a single bow-shaped function that
是一个单弓形函数
looks like this, so that
大概是这样
if you run gradient descent, we
所以如果对它使用梯度下降法
would be guaranteed that gradient descent, you know,
我们可以保证梯度下降法
would converge to the global minimum.
会收敛到该函数的全局最小值
And the problem of using the
但使用这个
the square cost function is that
平方代价函数的问题是
because of this very
因为中间的这个
non linear sigmoid function that
非常非线性的
appears in the middle here, J of
sigmoid函数的出现
theta ends up being
导致J(θ)成为
a non convex function if you
一个非凸函数
were to define it as the square cost function.
如果你要用平方函数定义它的话
So what we'd would like to do
所以我们想做的是
is to instead come up with
另外找一个
a different cost function that
不同的代价函数
is convex and so
它是凸函数
that we can apply a great
使得我们可以使用很好的算法
algorithm like gradient descent
如梯度下降法
and be guaranteed to find a global minimum.
而且能保证找到全局最小值
Here's a cost function that we're going to use for logistic regression.
这个代价函数便是我们要用在逻辑回归上的
We're going to say the cost
我们认为
or the penalty that the algorithm
这个算法要付的代价或者惩罚
pays if it outputs
如果输出值是h(x)
a value H of X.
或者换句话说
So, this is some number like 0.7
假如说预测值h(x)
where it predicts a value H
是一个数 比如0.7
of X. And the actual
而实际上
cost label turns out to
真实的标签值是y
be Y. The cost is
那么代价值将等于
going to be minus log
-log(h(X))
H of X if Y is equal 1.
当y=1时
And minus log, 1 minus
以及-log(1-h(X))
H of X if Y is equal to 0.
当y=0时
This looks like a pretty complicated function.
这看起来是个非常复杂的函数
But let's plot function to
但是让我们画出这个函数
gain some intuition about what it's doing.
可以直观地感受一下它在做什么
Let's start up with the case of Y equals 1.
我们从y=1这个情况开始
If Y is equal equal
如果y等于1
to 1, then the cost function
那么这个代价函数
is -log H of X, and
是-log(h(X))
if we plot that, so let's
如果我们画出它
say that the horizontal
我们将h(X)
axis is H of X.
画在横坐标上
So we know that a hypothesis
我们知道假设函数
is going to output a value between
的输出值
0 and 1.
是在0和1之间的
Right?
对吧？
So H of X that varies
所以h(X)的值
between 0 and 1.
在0和1之间变化
If you plot what this cost function looks like.
如果你画出这个代价函数的样子
You find that it looks like this.
你会发现它看起来是这样的
One way to see why the
理解这个函数为什么是这样的
plot like this it is because
一个方式是
if you were to plot log Z
如果你画出log(z)
with Z on the horizontal axis.
z在横轴上
Then that looks like that.
它看起来会是这样
And it's approach is minus infinity.
它趋于负无穷
So this is what the log function looks like.
这是对数函数的样子
And so this is 0, this is 1.
所以这里是0 这里是1
Here Z is of
显然 这里的Z
course playing the role  of
就是代表h(x)的角色
H of X.  And so
因此
minus log Z will look like this.
-log(Z)看起来这样
Right just flipping the sign.
就是翻转一下符号
Minus log Z. And we're
-log(Z)
interested only in the
我们所感兴趣的是
range of when this function
函数在0到1
goes between 0 and 1.
之间的这个区间
So, get rid of that.
所以 忽略那些
And so, we're just left with,
所以只剩下
you know, this part of the curve.
曲线的这部分
And that's what this curve on the left looks like.
这就是左边这条曲线的样子
Now this cost function
现在这个代价函数
has a few interesting and desirable properties.
有一些有趣而且很好的性质
First you notice that if
首先 你注意到
Y is equal to 1 and H of X is equal 1, in
如果y=1而且h(X)=1
other words, if the hypothesis
也就是说
exactly, you know, predicts
如果假设函数
H equals 1, and Y
刚好预测值是1
is exactly equal to what I predicted.
而且y刚好等于我预测的
Then the cost is equal 0.
那么这个代价值等于0
Right?
对吧？
That corresponds to, the curve doesn't actually flatten out.
这对应于… 这个曲线并不是平的
The curve is still going. First, notice
曲线还在继续走
that if H of X
首先 注意到如果h(x)=1
equals 1, if the hypothesis
如果假设函数
predicts that Y is equal to 1.
预测Y=1
And if indeed Y is
并且如果y确实等于1
equal to 1 then the cost is equal to 0.
那么代价值等于0
That corresponds to this point down here.
这对应于下面这个点
Right?
对吧？
If H of X is equal
如果h(X)=1
to 1, and we're only
这里我们只需要考虑
concerned the case that Y equals 1 here.
y=1的情况
But if H of X is equal to 1.
如果h(x)等于1
Then the cost is down here is equal to 0.
那么代价值等于0
And that is what we like it to be.
这是我们所希望的
Because, you know, if we
因为如果我们
correctly predict the output Y then the cost is 0.
正确预测了输出值y 那么代价值是0
But now, notice also
但是现在 同样注意到
that H of X approaches 0.
h(x)趋于0时
So, that's H. As the
所以 那是h
output of the hypothesis approaches 0
当假设函数的输出趋于0时
the cost blows up, and it goes to infinity.
代价值激增 并且趋于无穷
And what this does is
我们这样描述
it captures the intuition that if
体现出了这样一种直观的感觉
a hypothesis, you know, outputs 0.
那就是如果假设函数输出0
That's like saying, our hypothesis is
相当于说
saying, the chance of Y
我们的假设函数说
equals 1 is equal to 0.
Y=1的概率等于0
It's kind of like our going
这类似于
to our medical patient and saying,
我们对病人说
"The probability that you
你有一个恶性肿瘤的概率
have a malignant tumor, the
也就是说
probability that Y equals 1 is zero."
y=1的概率是0
So, it's like absolutely impossible that your
就是说你的肿瘤
tumor is malignant.
完全不可能是恶性的
But if it turns out that
然而结果是
the tumor, the patient's tumor, actually is malignant.
病人的肿瘤确实是恶性的
So if Y is equal to
所以如果y=1
1 even after we told them
即使我们告诉他们
you know, the probability of it happening is 0.
它发生的概率是0
It's absolutely impossible for it to be malignant.
它完全不可能是恶性的
But if we told them
如果我们告诉他们这个
this with that level of certainty,
和我们的确信程度
and we turn out to be wrong,
并且最后我们是错的
then we penalize the learning algorithm
那么我们用非常非常大的代价值
by a very, very large cost,
惩罚这个学习算法
and that's captured by having this
它是被这样体现出来
cost goes infinity if Y
这个代价值趋于无穷
equals 1 and H
如果y=1
of X approaches 0.
而h(x)趋于0
This might consider of
这是y=1时的情况
Y1, let's look at what
我们再来看看
the cost function looks like for Y0.
y=0时 代价值函数是什么样
If Y is equal to 0, then the cost
如果y=0
looks like this expression over here.
那么代价值是这个表达式
And if you plot
如果画出函数
the function minus log 1
-log(1-z)
minus Z what you
那么你得到的
get is the cost function actually looks like this.
代价函数实际上是这样
So, it goes from 0 to 1.
它从0到1
Something like that.
差不多这样
And so if you plot
如果你画出
the cost function for the case
y=0情况下的
of y equals zero, you find that it looks
代价函数
like this and what
你会发现大概是这样
this curve does is it
它现在所做的是
now blows up,
在h(X)趋于1时激增
and it goes to plus infinity as H of X goes to 1.
趋于正无穷
Because it's saying that
因为它是说
if Y turns out to be
如果最后发现
equal to 0, but we
y等于0
predicted that you know, Y is
而我们却几乎
equal to 1 with almost
非常肯定地预测
certainty with probability 1, then
y=1的概率是1
we end up paying a very large cost.
那么我们最后就要付出非常大的代价值
Let's plot the cost function for
（以下这一段和前面重复了）让我们画出y=0时的
the case of Y equals 0.
代价函数
So if Y equals 0 that's going to be our cost function.
所以如果y=0 这就是我们的代价值函数
If you look at this expression,
如果你看着这个表达式
and if you plot, you know, minus
然后你画出
log 1 minus Z, if
-log(1-Z)
you figure out what that looks like,
如果你清楚它是什么样的
you get a figure that looks like this.
你会得到这样一个图形
Where, which goes from 0
这样随着
to 1 with the Z
横轴上的z
axis on the horizontal axis.
从0到1
So If you take this cost
如果你画出
function and plot it for
y=0时的
the case of Y equals 0,
代价函数
what you get is
你会发现
that the cost function looks like this.
代价函数是这样的
And what this cost function
它所做的是
does is that it blows
代价函数会在这里激增
up or it goes to a
趋于正无穷
positive infinity as each
随着h(X)的增大
H of X goes to one
而趋近于1
and this captures the
这体现了这样一个直观的感觉
intuition that if a hypothesis
如果假设函数预测
predicted that, you know, H of
h(X)=1
X is equal to 1 with
并且非常确定
certainty, with like probability 1,
比如这样的概率是1
it's absolutely got to be Y equals 1.
认为y肯定是1
But if Y turned out to
但是最后发现
be equal to 0 then
y其实等于0
it makes sense to make the
这就必须要让假设函数
hypothesis, or make the learning algorithm pay a very large cost.
或者学习算法付出一个很大的代价
And conversely, if H
反过来
of X is equal to
如果h(x)=0
0 and Y equals zero,
而且y=0
then the hypothesis nailed it.
那么假设函数预测对了
The predicted Y is equal
预测的是y=0
to zero and it turns
并且y就是等于0
out Y is equal to zero
并且Y就是等于0
so at this point the cost
那么代价值函数在这点上
function is going to be 0.
应该等于0
In this video, we
在这个视频中
have defined the cost function
我们定义了
for a single training example.
单训练样本的代价函数
The topic of convexity analysis is beyond the scope of this course.
凸性分析的内容是超出这门课的范围的
But it is possible to show
但是可以证明
that with our particular choice
我们所选的
of cost function this would
代价值函数
give us a convex optimization problem
会给我们一个
as cost function, overall cost function
凸优化问题
J of theta will be
代价函数J(θ)会是一个凸函数
convex and local optima free.
并且没有局部最优值
In the next video we're going
在下一个视频中
to take these ideas of the
我们会把单训练样本的
cost function for a single
代价函数的这些理念
training example and develop that
进一步发展
further and define the
然后给出
cost function for the entire
整个训练集的代价函数的定义
training set, and we'll also
我们还会找到一种
figure out a simpler way to
比我们目前用的
write it than we have been using so far.
更简单的写法
And based on that will
基于这些推导出的结果
work out gradient descent, and
我们将应用梯度下降法
that will give us our logistic regression algorithm.
得到我们的逻辑回归算法